Here , they say that revenge is like a river .
And our actions are the dugouts guided by the current .
We say that revenge is like a river ,
whose bottom is reached
only when we drown .
BISSAU GUINEA-BISSAU
THE MILITARY DECLARES A COUP D 'ETAT
THEIR PLEDGE TO RESTORE ORDER LOOKS MORE LIKE BLOODSHED
THEIR TARGET : THE INTERNATIONAL DRUG TRADE
BAD NEWS FOR PUSHERS
UNLESS YOU HAVE A GETAWAY PLAN ...
BANGUI 'S HYENAS
GUNS FOR HIRE
LIVE BY FIRE
There 's a lot of bullshit out there about Bangui 's Hyenas .
Cannibals , sorcerers , shepherds turned into mercenaries .
Their names have echoed on battlefields ,
stories told at nightfall
to excite child soldiers
high on crack .
There !
Motherfuckers !
If there is even any evidence of their existence ,
no one has ever been able to say when or how they disappeared from memory ...
Hey Mexican ,
take care of that sweater ,
it 's the Juventus , not junk .
525 thousand .
And 500 thousand on Tony Montana 's delivery .
You hear that , Felix ?
Your foreskin face is worth more than a McLaren .
No one talks to me like that , you bastard .
I had a McLaren before you could even hold a gun .
What a clown !
These clowns are the only ones who can get you to Dakar in one piece .
Unless you want to jump out here ?
Right ?
OK .
Fuck !
We 're losing fuel .
The tank is fucked .
We won 't run for an hour .
Where are we ?
- Over Gambia . - No !
Not Gambia . Dakar !
My contact , Dakar !
If you don 't take me to Dakar , I 'll kill you , motherfuckers !
I 'll kill you ! I 'll kill him and him !
Minuit ...
It must have been a bullet .
- Carry on to Senegal . - What ?
To Saloum .
Oh , for fuck 's sake .
These fucking Guineans ruined my Versace .
There .
Seriously , you grew up here ?
And your Wolof is still as bad as ever .
I 've spent enough time in Saloum
to know I don 't want to stay here very long .
With all those dead civilians , the Guineans will call the Senegalese .
We 're going to have the police on our ass .
That 's why I 've got the brain and you have the muscles .
The muscles say you midget better have a plan .
Or ?
Or I 'll bury you
and I 'll get out of here to meet some chicks in Cape Verde .
Don 't forget to kiss my ass when you wake up .
A knife .
Not a bullet .
It was done before we even took off .
Someone is playing us .
Why don 't we ask him ?
I was with him all the way . He 's clean .
The cartel is paying a million to bring him back alive ,
why would they fuck us halfway ?
How do we know he doesn 't want to fuck us ?
That he didn 't pay a team in Dakar to take us out and steal the gold ?
Let 's knock him on the head , problem solved .
Mr. Brain , what 's your damn plan now ?
There 's a place .
Eight hours walking , if we go fast .
There will be fuel and resin to stop the leak .
As soon as that 's done , we 're out of here .
If that fails , we have enough to buy another plane .
And that 's where it started .
Sine-Saloum ,
where the river embraces the sea .
A sacred and protected land ,
home of Senghor and land of the great Senegalese marabouts .
Located north of The Gambia and south of Senegal .
Sprinkled with islets and villages on kilometers of lagoons .
Land of myths and cursed kings .
There 's no better hiding place
for these mercenaries on horses .
OK . Go ahead .
I know the camp and the owner .
It 's isolated , far away from the town .
BAOBAB CAMP SALOUM DELTA
The nearest village is 10 km away .
Three days here and they will forget about us .
You let me do the talking .
Welcome to the Baobab .
" Abandon all hope , ye who enter here " .
Usually , the spirits of the Saloum are quieter .
And not as well-dressed .
Omar ?
Do I know you ?
My apologies for arriving unexpectedly .
I have fond memories of this place ,
so I decided to bring my colleagues .
I don 't remember you .
And I have a photographic memory .
It was a long time ago . You haven 't aged a bit .
The Saloum preserves .
Do you have four rooms for three nights ?
I 'm afraid you 're too late , I rented the last two this morning .
Follow me . We 'll try colleagues in the region .
Even if I 'm the only one practicing my formula .
Oh , really ? Which is ?
You pay nothing but what you consider fair to give .
Oh , really ?
Interesting .
Loyalty Bar !
Two glasses of Jack .
One for me and one for my friend , the curly one .
Instead , guests commit to perform
daily tasks necessary for the functioning of the camp .
Which certainly isn 't for everyone .
For alcoholic drinks , your chore is to clean the bar .
What ?
Excuse me , Sirs .
Ladies and gents .
I hope you enjoyed your drinks .
You 're gonna do your chores .
Did you see how he waited to fuck me ?
Didn 't I tell you to shut up and let me talk ?
Well , it appears two cabins have become available .
Two instead of four . Is that okay ?
It 's perfect !
We 'll settle in while our friend does his chores .
Saloum is a natural sanctuary .
It 's our duty to preserve it .
Tasks are designated every morning , with other guests .
If everyone accepts ,
an OK from the group will do .
- OK . - Good .
Here are your cabins .
Hot water and electricity included .
Please join us for dinner .
Let 's get to know each other .
You can do your bar chores after dinner ,
no problem .
So we pay nothing , but we 're their bitches for three days .
This is your plan ?
Fall-back plan .
We 're here for fuel , resin and relaxation .
For that , we have to gain their trust .
His fear has gotten worse . He can 't even ride a canoe .
Chaka won 't shake off his fear .
He 's preparing for something .
Something ... he isn 't telling us .
Lie down .
So ?
We have to get out of here .
There 's an eye on us .
You 're useless , you can 't sing ,
- you can 't cook , you 're useless ! - I can 't cook ?
- All you do is talking . - And what do you do ? Nothing .
Welcome !
Please join us .
Thank you .
- Good evening . - Good evening .
Everything OK ?
Really good ! The cabins are perfect !
First of all , William , Solange and Eva
had to leave us for health reasons .
Allahu akbar .
But providence has brought us a new group of holidaymakers .
This young artist couple joined us two days ago ,
Younce and Sephora .
Not couple , collaborators .
Ex-couple , new collaborators .
Stay strong !
Thank you !
Here , we have Awa , who joined us yesterday .
And my right-hand man and man of confidence , Salamane .
Good evening to the new arrivals .
If you need anything , I am at your disposal .
And you , my dear friends ?
Cheikh , Rufin , Maudou and Felipe .
Felipe is a bit twitchy , isn 't he ?
Mosquitoes and thiep don 't agree with him .
Neither does Baobab powder , right ?
Stay strong .
Taste this thiou . Tell me what you think ,
and bon appÃ © tit .
You 're keeping your gloves on ?
I prefer to keep my hands clean .
And when do you leave ?
In three days . Back to Kedougou .
South ?
Gold .
We work at the gold mine .
Felipe is our contact for South American investors .
So what brings you to our beautiful Sine-Saloum region ?
Education and culture .
Exploiting a land we don 't understand
can quickly turn into destructive post-colonialism .
Saloum is a good start for understanding the habits and customs of our country ,
that 's what I think .
Good .
Senegal needs partners , not operators .
Senegal needs money ,
not luggage carriers for honkies .
" No one can imagine how the grain of the poor
has fed the cows of the rich in our country . "
Good ! Any man quoting Thomas Sankara at dinner
deserves the leadership of the table .
Can I exchange that for a transfer of chores to our local Tupac ?
Tupac didn 't sell any more than I did on the mainland .
And you , Awa ?
What do you think about Upper Volta ?
That even monkeys can culture themselves .
I forgot to mention , Awa is deaf and mute . But she reads lips .
Culture can be shared .
Tell us your story .
You won 't like the script .
It 's the story of a Mexican drug trafficker evacuated by Senegalese Mercenaries .
Maybe it would be better for everyone to understand your conversation ?
Mr. Cheikh ?
What else ?
I am the last to arrive . This camp has no means of contact .
I 'm the only one who knows .
Please , sir ...
If you 're the only one who knows and they don 't understand ,
what 's to stop us from shooting you here ,
after Salamane 's excellent thiou ?
Because I 'm going with you .
What 's this bullshit ?
Wow . Even gorillas can learn sign language .
Either you take me or I 'll expose you .
Please forgive his rudeness .
When it 's about gold mining , all means of communication are good .
Gold miners who know Sankara and sign language .
You impress me more by the minute , Mr Cheikh .
You 'll be sick to death of us .
What better honour than a Baobab dinner in Saloum ?
Souley , my old friend !
Omar !
You always appear like an ill omen .
Please let me introduce , Captain Souleymane Fale .
Captain ? Captain of ... ?
Police .
Not of a canoe .
What brings you to this remote part of the country , Captain ?
A few days of rest outside Dakar , to get my thoughts together .
Especially since the coup in Guinea Bissau .
It seems to be heating up at the border ...
That 's why I 'm here .
Relaxation !
The purest strain of the Dakar police .
Captain Souleymane Fale , professional Flag drinker !
Omar , you 're too much .
How are you ?
Good night .
Please excuse me . I 'm kind of worn out .
Very good evening . Thank you for everything .
Hey !
Not bad .
Careful Corporal , I hit hard .
I expect your answer tomorrow .
Geez .
We leave you five minutes and you 've already started to fiddle .
A punk kid full of threats and a cop from Dakar .
What 's next ? James Brown ?
And you ,
I 'm starting to think your fetishes are a magnet for trouble .
What you 're hiding ...
will kill us .
Rafa didn 't come back tonight .
Omar has called for us .
Now .
Please , don 't start , Younce .
What have you been up to all night ?
Did you fuck all night ?
None of your business .
When I say be discreet and blend in ,
what didn 't you understand ?
You said : fuel , resin and relaxation .
We don 't have fuel or resin .
So I 'm relaxing .
May we start , now that the latecomers are here ?
Salamane is going to pass among you .
Please dig into the jar to pick your duty .
There are two identical papers , each for two people .
The cop arrived last .
If the girl 's story is true , then he 's busted us too .
Let 's go to Gambia before things get out of hand .
Thank you , Salamane .
Those whose task I am calling , please raise their hands .
Delivery to the Village .
Salamane and Mr. Maudou will go to the village
to deliver the goods for the villagers .
The Beauty of the Camp ?
Again !
The name may be misleading ,
but the task is essential to the well-being of others .
Before the old man finally resurrects Biafra ,
have you made up your mind ?
Who dies ? The girl ? The cop ? The Mexican ?
Bird Island ?
The Delta Fishermen .
Delta Fishermen ?
Maybe the names are too fancy ,
but they allow our guests not to feel too ...
- Exploited ? - You could put it that way .
We maintain our quality of life
thanks to the villagers to whom we render service .
Guests rarely leave without leaving a gift . Even a small one .
And what are we defending with horses and guns ?
We have inherited the best task of the day .
First I thought about taking the quads .
You have quads ?
Two beautiful babes . But maybe a less frontal approach
will better suit what we 're going to do .
Hoping you can shoot ?
There are no good shooters , only good targets .
BIRD RESERVE SALOUM DELTA
You 're the queen of conversation .
I 'll talk when I get my answer .
Show me some respect . I 'm surely your elder . Swamp Toad .
Take me with you or I 'll expose you . Simple .
I don 't care , but I 'm curious ,
why do you want to run away with the devil ?
You , devils ?
Do we look like UNICEF ?
Bangui 's Hyenas . Half Senegalese , half Central Africa .
Chaka , Rafa , Papa Minuit .
Same who disarmed the Seleka in Central Africa without firing a bullet .
The same who cleared Freetown of the RUF .
Same ones who foiled the coup
against Konan Bedie in Ivory Coast .
Heroes .
Oh yeah ? Where did you hear that ?
Stories about heroes travel faster than bullets .
DONATIONS - DAIRIES
DIOLAS VILLAGE SALOUM DELTA
What 's going on here ?
For years , Omar has been redistributing goods
to the villagers in exchange for their services .
The elders negotiate . The wrestlers collect .
DONATIONS - MEDICINES
DJIFFER VILLAGE SALOUM DELTA
The village of Djiffer is as close as we get to civilization .
Here we fight one of the evils affecting us most .
An evil that requires BB guns can 't be that threatening .
It all depends on the threat .
Our friend helps to spot them before they get away .
The Saloum is home to one of the largest varieties of fish in the world .
Species ranging from 7 to 70 kg , depending on the location .
BB guns ?
What am I looking at ?
Poachers .
They come to Djiffer to load up equipment .
They go up the delta to fish with explosives .
The three little pigs there ? They don 't seem that dangerous .
They destroy our ecosystem and threaten our local fishermen .
MANGROVE SALOUM DELTA
You have to put them in the ground to make them grow .
Looking at them is not enough .
Tulum .
It grows in Tulum .
I know what it is . I grew up with it .
Why is it so important here ?
Mangrove is like everything else that grows in Saloum .
Harmless in appearance , but extremely hardy .
Coveted by foreign operators ,
like your bosses with their gold .
It 's gold that you mine , isn 't it ?
Your Interpol file says that the cartel has issued a contract on your head .
It 's smart to stay here
and disguise yourself as a crazy drug addict to disappear .
And if you 're the dealer ,
I 'm guessing they 're the Hyenas ...
Hey ! Calm down .
My teams are already in place .
They 'll move during dinner .
Until then , you 'll help me keep the Hyenas distracted
and away from their weapons .
Like I said ,
what grows in the Saloum may seem harmless ,
but is tough as hell . And tenacious .
Where did you learn to shoot like that ?
A few years in the Army ... And a rifle at home .
Don 't tell Captain Fale .
So we have that in common .
What ?
The battlefield .
What conflict ?
Angola , Mozambique , Casamance .
A dark time in my life .
But now I have become an expert tour guide .
You ?
Congo , Central African Republic , Sierra Leone , Ivory Coast .
But now I have become an expert logistician .
Speaking of logistics , can I ask you a favor ?
From soldier to soldier .
I need fuel and resin . Do you have that ?
I have enough to pay for it .
A few kilometers from the camp there is an old village .
We have a shed there .
You 'll find everything you need .
- Thank you . If there 's anything ... - No , no , no .
Not between us . Especially after today .
Now let 's face those who didn 't get the chance
to shoot poachers ' butts .
Little bitch .
Come , taco face . We need to talk .
No , he stays here , I have to talk with him .
The girl ... she knows too much about us .
This is getting too complicated .
The village they deal with , something 's wrong with it .
- What village ? - We need to get out of here .
There 's resin and fuel . We get it , we get out .
Minuit , you take care of Salamane , he knows where it 's stored .
Where 's Felix ?
There .
The cop has kept him for questioning .
We meet at dinner in two hours , you know what you have to do .
We stick to the plan .
I have to be there , and you too .
You ? How ?
Where were you ? You always arrive after the battle !
I was just talking about our mission this afternoon .
A bullet in the butts and they turned tail to run .
Omar 's been talking about you all day .
Military ?
Another time , another life .
Some guests are missing .
It seems that Awa has decided not to join us .
After all , no one is a prisoner here .
Speaking of prisoners ,
Mr Souleymane ,
is there a problem with my client ?
Rufin told me that you detained him for questioning .
Oh , no .
I was curious about your gold mining project .
Senegalese are protective of their land .
You know how that is . You 're half-Serrere .
Only the good half .
Well , I know that for many of us ,
today wasn 't pleasant ,
but I would like to hear your experiences .
Mr. Rufin , would you like to begin ?
I counted birds .
Birds everywhere .
I think there was a shack over there ?
There was a shack , wasn 't there ?
A shack ?
Made of irregular sheet metal .
It looked like ...
a cattle crate .
The days can be very hot here ,
and the nights ...
freezing .
There were reeds all along the river ,
and a lot more tall grass .
Everything seemed ...
More threatening .
More hostile .
I remember feeling so lonely .
So weak .
Every step towards freedom .
I tore it up .
With every breath I took flight .
Because every part of the child that was still alive ,
you tore it up .
Every night ,
for weeks .
You defiled the 11-year-old child I was ,
even while you promised safety and protection .
At that time ,
we child soldiers
called him Colonel Remington .
Because , on the battlefield ,
he was the one who carried this .
Also because he was the only one
who promised us paradise .
Here ,
in Saloum .
Chaka ...
Omar , what did you do ?
You should never have come to Senegal .
Units 1 and 2 !
It was you !
You have lied to us from the beginning .
You lied to us so we 'd follow you .
If I told you why , you wouldn 't let me come .
The only option was to land here .
Units 1 and 2 ! Answer me !
They won 't answer you .
Unit 1 2 ! Answer !
They left this morning
richer than when they came .
Felix !
Oh fuck !
What the fuck did you do to him ?
We need to get inside the cabins !
It 's started !
What has started ? !
Felix !
What does he have ?
He 's dead . Rafa , the cop .
Minuit , you take the musicians .
Let 's get the weapons and go to the shed .
And what about our new friend ?
You 're dead ! I 'm exposing you .
Too late .
What 's wrong with him ?
He 's sleeping , can 't you see ?
He 's dead . And if we stay here , we 'll join him .
And Omar ?
You two shut up , ok ?
What an asshole !
No stab wounds .
No bullet holes .
No sign of poison .
Do you smell that ?
Sulfur ?
- Witchcraft ? - No .
A man couldn 't have done this .
Spirits can 't penetrate inside the cabin ,
because of the artificial light and the magnetic waves .
What the fuck now ?
What 's going on ?
Power outage .
Untie me , I can handle it .
What is he doing ?
Untie me !
- It 's started . - What 's started ?
Omar was their guardian .
You killed the only barrier between them and us .
They 're coming to take us , one by one .
Enough !
We gather up any weapons and you take us to the shed .
Guns won 't do any good .
You killed his ferryman .
What exactly happened to him ?
Your grigris and initiations won 't help you here .
Bainuk 's spirits are older and stronger than your bwiti .
Bainuks disappeared from Sine-Saloum hundreds of years ago .
Gana Sira Bana never left .
He is here and he reigns .
The curse of Sira Bana .
Let us go !
It 's bullshit !
Sereres dominate the Saloum ,
Bainouks are in Casamance .
The Bainuks were there before them .
Some of them sold their land for their king 's head .
Gana Sira Bana .
Who promised to curse this earth and let it die .
This part of Saloum is cursed forever .
Only a handful of Diolas have been allowed to stay here .
As King Bainuk 's servants .
The villagers and their ears .
Your iboga will make you resistant , it is true ,
but you 'll still hear them .
The spirits of Sira Bana .
And when you hear them , you will die .
They devour your senses one after the other .
Speech , sight , hearing , touch , smell .
You will lose everything , until your body no longer belongs to you .
You see ?
You 're as human as we are .
A bitch slap and you shut your mouth .
Omar made a pact with the spirits
to make this place accessible again .
- How do we fight them ? - We don 't fight them .
We have to run away or they 'll catch us .
To avoid hearing them , we have to cover our ears .
Listen ,
I have headphones in my studio bag .
- Four sets . - We 're eight .
There are construction headsets in the shed .
The workers use them for the camp work .
There must be around ten .
Do you count eight ? We 're three .
And we 've yet to decide if we can trust you or not .
We don 't know these people , we don 't give a damn about them .
We have a deaf-mute with us .
Do you wanna get rid of her ?
We help each other to get out of here alive ,
and then if you want to act like a hero you can .
For now , I 'm going to get the comedian 's headsets .
Let 's go .
Bring the vehicle closer .
And why would I do that ?
And then what ? You 'll kill me like the old man ?
You 're on the run .
It 's a four-seats plane
and a seat is now free . It 's up to you .
Four seats ? You knew from the beginning that I couldn 't come ...
And how do you know I 'm on the run ?
Why didn 't you say anything the first time ?
Because you didn 't say anything the first time .
Once you get the headsets , you 'll leave the others behind ?
We 're not nannies .
Like the civilians in Bissau ?
They were already dead .
We don 't hurt civilians .
So it 's you . Chaka ! The leader of the Hyenas .
I want to join you ...
We 're not alone .
What ?
As well as the spirits of the mountain ?
Those things out there
are trying to get inside our heads .
Omar ,
what did you do ... ?
The diolas from the village .
They 'll do anything to make us hear the spirits .
If they 're human , they can be killed .
Mashallah ! With what ? Our fingernails ?
Are there guns in here ?
Hammers and axes .
Nothing else .
We 're not military .
You 're going to take us to the shed .
We need fuel and resin .
The cars are out of order , but we have Omar 's quads ,
so we have four seats .
Salamane , Rafa , you 're with me .
Captain , you 're coming too .
You stay with Minuit .
No way , I 'm coming too .
Don 't you trust me ?
No !
But as a guarantee , I keep the gun .
No way .
Give me your gun .
Rafa .
Here .
Prepare the dugout for escape .
Are you going to leave us here ?
You two , barricade yourselves in .
I 'm sorry for what he did to you .
Together to the end .
Where is it ?
Come on , move .
- What the fuck is this ? - Fuel .
Chaka .
Rafa .
Stay here .
Captain ,
you go first .
Chaka .
There are two near the hut .
I fear it 's too late for them . But I have to try .
What are you doing with the children ?
Witchcraft , sacrifices ? What did you summon here ?
I 'm listening .
He was using them !
They 're his currency with the spirits .
In exchange for what ?
I know Remington .
He wouldn 't do that for a piece of beach !
What did he find here ?
He found the entity !
What entity ?
Bastard !
I have the headsets . Let 's get out of here .
The quads !
Fuck !
Souley !
Holy shit !
Souley ! Souley !
They 're coming , we have to go !
Let 's get out of here !
Help , Mr. Maudou !
I can 't see anything .
Who is it ?
Awa ?
Don 't leave me like this .
Don 't leave me .
Please ... Don 't leave me like this .
Please ...
I 'm holding them .
Now that you are here ,
I will not leave defeated .
Together till the end .
See you soon .
Not today .
What 's wrong with him ?
Brother , you 're gonna get inside , or I 'll force you .
Fear of water .
Minuit told me about Omar .
You came to take his place .
Your soul is heavy now ,
you 're ready .
I 'm taking you with me .
Chaka .
Here , they say that revenge is like a river
and our actions are the dugouts
guided by the current .
We say that revenge is like a river ,
whose bottom is reached
only when we drown .